Guide to the Emilie F. Miller papers, 1987-1991
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Emilie F. Miller papers
1987-1991
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Emilie F. Miller
C0048
48 linear feet (36 boxes)
The Emile F. Miller papers contain materials pertaining to her service in the Virginia State Legislature. Included in the collection are campaign material, subject files, bills and resolutions, correspondence, committee information, constituent files, and information on the Virginia Military Institute controversy.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Emilie F. Miller in 1996.
Biographical Information
Emilie F. Miller is a local activist and former politician from Northern Virginia. She was the first woman senator to represent the Fairfax area. In 1968 she joined the Fairfax County Democratic Committee, and became its chair from 1976 to 1980. In 1974 she joined the Virginia Democratic State Central Committee. Long serving Virginia Senator Adelard L. Brault (1966-1982) hired her as his legislative aid in 1980. Two years later, Senator Brault retired and endorsed Miller's candidacy for the post. Her opponent in 1983 was three-term Republican mayor of Fairfax City, John W. Russell. Early in the race, Miller labeled Russell a sexist for his opposition to the Equal Rights Amendment, and for his comments about women serving in combat as being dangerous enough without guns. However, she lost the election by one-percent of the vote.
During the interim between her candidacies, Miller remained active in state and local politics. Virginia Governor Charles S. Robb appointed her to the State Mental Health and Mental Retardation Board (1982- 1988). The Fairfax County Board of Supervisors appointed her to the Child Abuse Prevention Task Force (1984-1987). She was also hired as legislative consultant to the Virginia Federation of Business and Professional Women (1986-1987). Her activism in mental health, family and community services, and woman's rights carried over into her term as Virginia senator.
In 1987 Miller ran for a second time against Russell. This time the Equal Rights Amendment was not an issue, but she maintained strong support from feminists, and was endorsed by the National Woman's Political Caucus of Northern Virginia. Narrowly defeating Russell by 180 votes, Miller set off on an ambitious and successful freshman term. She was the first woman elected to the Senate from Northern Virginia. She was the only freshman to receive four committee assignments. She was the only woman to serve on the Education and Health Committee. And she was the first Virginia legislator to serve on the Labor Committee of the National Conference of State Legislators.
During her first and second sessions (1988-1989) Miller focused on issues dealing with mental health and substance abuse. She introduced many bills, and several passed. One successful bill allowed future funding for mental health, mental retardation and substance abuse services; another allowed the study of the criminal prosecution of individuals who abuse patients of state facilities for the mentally disabled. An upshot of the latter bill was the establishment of the State Board of Mental Health, Mental Retardation, and Substance Abuse Services, which developed regulations defining abuse and facilitated prosecution of those at fault. Miller successfully amended the state budget by two million dollars for use by mental health services, and ensured that state funding would follow the six-year plan established by the Virginia Department of Mental Health, Mental Retardation, and Substance Abuse.
Dominating Miller's 1990 and 1991 sessions was the nationally known Virginia Military Institute (VMI) controversy. The U.S. Department of justice was suing the state of Virginia for denying admittance to a woman who had applied to VMI. Virginia Attorney General Mary Sue Terry stood behind VMI's decision not to enroll women at the traditionally all-male institute. But Miller objected to the practice, calling it sexist and unconstitutional, especially since the school was publicly funded. Consequently she introduced legislation providing that "all public institutions of higher education shall admit qualified students without regard to race, sex, religion, national origin, or political affiliation."
In addition to the VMI controversy, Miller continued to legislate for mental health, woman's rights, and family services. Her successful legislation included the consideration of a defendant's mental health in death penalty cases; authorization for Fairfax County and Fairfax City to regulate child care services and facilities; the regulation of advertising by licensed treatment facilities for the mentally ill; the development of alternative levels of care for psychiatric and substance abuse treatment and insurance coverage that will reimburse for such care; the designation of March as Virginia Woman's History Month; and the designation of April 22, 1990 as Earth day in Virginia.
Among her other achievements during her term included a public-private partnership on three pilot projects testing the use of natural gas in Virginia Department of Transportation vehicles; the extension of health insurance coverage requirements to include mammograms; an increase in the income and net worth limitations for senior citizens to qualify for property tax relief; simplified procedures for citizens to obtain government information and attend public government business; and increased civil penalties for zoning code violations.
While a senator, Miller was assigned to four standing committees: Education and Health, General Laws, Local Government, and Rehabilitation and Social Services. She was further assigned to several legislative subcommittees, such as the Parental Drug Exposure and Abuse Committee, and the Early Intervention Services for Handicapped Infants and Toddlers Committee.
Miller attempted reelection in 1991, focusing on education and abortion issues, but lost to her Republican opponent, Jane H. Woods.
Scope and Content
The Emile F. Miller Papers contain materials pertaining to her service in the Virginia State Legislature. Included in the collection are campaign material, subject files, bills and resolutions, correspondence, committee information, constituent files, and information on the Virginia Military Institute controversy.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by topic, including personal files, legislative issues, bills and resolutions, campaigns, and committees.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
The George Mason University Special Collections and Archives also holds other collections for research on the political life of women in Northern Virginia such as the, the, and the.
Index Terms
Persons:
Miller, Emilie F.
Corporate Names:
Virginia Military Institute.
Geographical Names:
Virginia--Politics and government--1951-
Subjects:
Mental health services--Virginia.; Women and the military--United States.; Women legislators--Virginia.; Women politicians--Virginia.; Women political activists--Virginia.; Women's rights--United States.
Contents List
- Emilie F.Miller Collection
  - Abortion - General (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Abortion - Guidelines and Pamphlets [1 of 3] (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Abortion - Guidelines and Pamphlets [2 of 3] (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - Abortion - Guidelines and Pamphlets [3 of 3] (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - Abortion - Parental Notification Correspondence 1990 [1 of 3] (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - Abortion - Parental Notification Correspondence 1990 [2 of 3] (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - Abortion - Parental Notification Correspondence [3 of 3] (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - Abortion - Press Clippings (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - Abortion - Advertisements (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - AIDS (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control Board [ ABC Board ] (Folder 11, Box 1)
  - American Association University Women [ AAUW] (Folder 12, Box 1)
  - American Business Women's Association [ ABWA] (Folder 13, Box 1)
  - American Flag (Folder 14, Box 1)
  - American Federation Labor - CIO, [ AFL] (Folder 15, Box 1)
  - American Legion (Folder 16, Box 1)
  - American Mental Health Fund (Folder 17, Box 1)
  - Arab American Organization List (Folder 18, Box 1)
  - Attorney General - Senate Suite (Folder 19, Box 1)
  - Babe Ruth Baseball Team - State Championship (Folder 20, Box 1)
  - Gerald L.Baliles Aministration (Folder 21, Box 1)
  - National Association of Bank Women - [NABW] 1989 (Folder 22, Box 1)
  - Fairfax Bar Association ,Fairfax (Folder 23, Box 1)
  - Beyer,Donald Jr. (Folder 24, Box 1)
  - Blake Lake [Truck Prohibition] (Folder 25, Box 1)
  - Blue Cross/ Blue Shield and Others (Folder 26, Box 1)
  - Boards and Commissions (Folder 27, Box 1)
  - Breast Cancer (Folder 28, Box 1)
  - Budget Process - Virginia (Folder 29, Box 1)
  - Business [ Virginia ] (Folder 30, Box 1)
  - Business and Professional Women - BPW (Folder 31, Box 1)
  - Bypass Round [Washington D.C. ] (Folder 32, Box 1)
  - Catholic Charities - Arlington Diocese (Folder 33, Box 1)
  - Catholic Church (Folder 34, Box 1)
  - Catholic Schools [ Arlington Diocese] (Folder 35, Box 1)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives (Folder 36, Box 1)
  - Center in the Square [Cultural Complex] (Folder 37, Box 1)
  - Central Fairfax Chamber of Commerce (Folder 38, Box 1)
  - Certificate of Public Need [Report] (Folder 39, Box 1)
  - Charlottesville [Tourism] (Folder 40, Box 1)
  - Chesapeake Bay [Environment Council] [1 of 3] (Folder 41, Box 1)
  - Chesapeake Bay [Environment Council] [ 2 of 3] (Folder 42, Box 1)
  - Chesapeake Bay [ Environment Council] [3 of 3] (Folder 43, Box 1)
  - Child Abuse [Virginia Treatment Center for Children] (Folder 44, Box 1)
  - Child Abuse and Neglect [Virginia for Child Abuse Prevention] (Folder 45, Box 1)
  - Children [Virginia Department for Children] (Folder 46, Box 1)
  - Children - Virginia Department of Child Protection Priorities (Folder 47, Box 1)
  - Child Support Enforcement [Handbook] (Folder 48, Box 1)
  - Chiropractics [Association of Vienna ] (Folder 49, Box 1)
  - Civic Association Letters (Folder 1, Box 2)
  - Civic Association - Fairfax City (Folder 2, Box 2)
  - Civic Association Lists [1 of 2] (Folder 3, Box 2)
  - Civic Association Lists [2 of 2] (Folder 4, Box 2)
  - Citizen Action (Folder 5, Box 2)
  - Citizens for Balanced Growth (Folder 6, Box 2)
  - Citizens on Sensible Taxation (Folder 7, Box 2)
  - Clean Air Act [Federal] (Folder 8, Box 2)
  - Clean Water Action October 1990 (Folder 9, Box 2)
  - Colonial Williamsburg Foundation February ,1991 (Folder 10, Box 2)
  - Commendations (Folder 11, Box 2)
  - Computer Crime Bill (Folder 12, Box 2)
  - Condominium Act (Folder 13, Box 2)
  - Conflict of Interest Report (Folder 14, Box 2)
  - Center for Conflict Analysis and Resolution, George Mason University (Folder 15, Box 2)
  - Constitution United States [ Article V] (Folder 16, Box 2)
  - Consultants (Folder 17, Box 2)
  - Contract Services Administration (Folder 18, Box 2)
  - Courts of Justice Letter 1990 (Folder 19, Box 2)
  - Courts ,Supreme [ Rehnquist's Court] September 11, 1988 (Folder 20, Box 2)
  - Crime - [Virginia] (Folder 21, Box 2)
  - Cubs - Media General (Folder 22, Box 2)
  - Cut - Through Traffic (Folder 23, Box 2)
  - Day Care - [Children Care Facilities] (Folder 24, Box 2)
  - Dees, Morris - [Southern Poverty Law Center] (Folder 25, Box 2)
  - Democratic Caucus (Folder 26, Box 2)
  - Democratic Leadership Council [1 of 2] (Folder 27, Box 2)
  - Democratic Leadership Council [2 of 2] (Folder 28, Box 2)
  - Democratic National Committee (Folder 29, Box 2)
  - Democratic Party of Virginia [1 of 2] (Folder 30, Box 2)
  - Democratic Party of Virginia [2 of 2] (Folder 31, Box 2)
  - Democrats 2000 (Folder 32, Box 2)
  - Department of Motor Vehicles - DMV (Folder 33, Box 2)
  - Domestic Relations (Folder 34, Box 2)
  - Downtown Fairfax Coalition (Folder 35, Box 2)
  - Drake University - [ Alumni Magazine] (Folder 36, Box 2)
  - Drugs - [Corporation Against Drug Abuse] (Folder 37, Box 2)
  - Dulles Airport - [DART] (Folder 38, Box 2)
  - Dulles Toll Road (Folder 39, Box 2)
  - Education - [Board] (Folder 40, Box 2)
  - Education and Health ,Higher Education Subcommittee 1990 (Folder 41, Box 2)
  - Department of Education (Folder 42, Box 2)
  - Education Funding for Children in Training Centers and State Facilities, Department Study (Folder 43, Box 2)
  - Education -Preschool - Material for Speech (Folder 44, Box 2)
  - Electronic Data Systems - EDS (Folder 45, Box 2)
  - Equals Rights Amendment - ERA (Folder 46, Box 2)
  - Ethos Foundation Advisory Committee (Folder 47, Box 2)
  - Fairfax Center Transportation Association (Folder 48, Box 2)
  - Fairfax City (Folder 49, Box 2)
  - Fairfax City - Commission for Women (Folder 50, Box 2)
  - Fairfax City - Faxing of Absentee Ballots (Folder 51, Box 2)
  - Fairfax County Chamber of Commerce (Folder 52, Box 2)
  - Fairfax County Council of PTA (Folder 53, Box 2)
  - Fairfax County Public Hearing [1 of 2] 1989 (Folder 54, Box 2)
  - Fairfax County Public Hearing [2 of 2] (Folder 55, Box 2)
  - Fairfax County Public Schools (Folder 56, Box 2)
  - Fairfax County Real Estate Tax Exemption (Folder 57, Box 2)
  - Fairfax Falls Church Community Services Board (Folder 58, Box 2)
  - Fairfax Host Lions Club (Folder 59, Box 2)
  - Fairfax Opportunities Unlimited (Folder 60, Box 2)
  - Faith Mission Home (Folder 61, Box 2)
  - Family Support Subsidy Program (Folder 62, Box 2)
  - FCAA - Arts for Special Audiences (Folder 63, Box 2)
  - Flag Burning (Folder 64, Box 2)
  - Form Letters 1989 (Folder 65, Box 2)
  - Center for Women in Politics,Government - George Mason University (Folder 66, Box 2)
  - Guests Book (Folder 67, Box 2)
  - FCPL Guide to the 1991 VA General Assembly (Folder 68, Box 2)
  - [ Certificates] - Items which were framed (Folder 69, Box 2)
  - General Obligation Bonds Co-Sponsor (Folder 1, Box 3)
  - George Mason University (Folder 2, Box 3)
  - George Mason University - Institute for Learning in Retirement (Folder 3, Box 3)
  - Goodwin House West - [ Approval of Crosswalk on South Jefferson street] (Folder 4, Box 3)
  - Virginia Governor's School (Folder 5, Box 3)
  - Graduation Parties - [Virginia] (Folder 6, Box 3)
  - Grayson Commission (Folder 7, Box 3)
  - Green Virginia 2000 [ Civic Tree Planting Program] (Folder 8, Box 3)
  - Virginia Ground Water (Folder 9, Box 3)
  - Group Homes (Folder 10, Box 3)
  - Gulf Crisis [Family Support Group Representation] (Folder 11, Box 3)
  - Guns Control Law [Instant Check] (Folder 12, Box 3)
  - Gunston Hall (Folder 13, Box 3)
  - Gypsy Moth Pest Suppression (Folder 14, Box 3)
  - Head Injury [Virginia Head Injury Foundation] (Folder 15, Box 3)
  - Health Care (Folder 16, Box 3)
  - Health Care for all Virginia People (Folder 17, Box 3)
  - Heart Association [ American Heart Association] (Folder 18, Box 3)
  - Hemophilia (Folder 19, Box 3)
  - Hermes Paris [Opening of Store] (Folder 20, Box 3)
  - Anita Hill [Professor ,University of Oklahoma] (Folder 21, Box 3)
  - Hill and Knowlton [State and Local Public Affairs] (Folder 22, Box 3)
  - Hispana [Latino - Quarterly Publication] (Folder 23, Box 3)
  - Historic Preservation Funding 1990 (Folder 24, Box 3)
  - Department of Historic Resources (Folder 25, Box 3)
  - Virginia Association of Homes for Adults (Folder 26, Box 3)
  - Horse Center [Virginia] (Folder 27, Box 3)
  - Hugh L.Gordon - Corporations and Taxes (Folder 28, Box 3)
  - Housing (Folder 29, Box 3)
  - H.O.V. Lanes (Folder 30, Box 3)
  - Hunting on the Potomac (Folder 31, Box 3)
  - I - 66 Coalition Noise Barriers (Folder 32, Box 3)
  - Virginia's Indians (Folder 33, Box 3)
  - Infant Mortality [ 1 of 2] (Folder 34, Box 3)
  - Infant Mortality [2 of 2] (Folder 35, Box 3)
  - America's Infrastructure (Folder 36, Box 3)
  - Re: HB 335 Insurance [1 of 2] (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Re: HB 335 Insurance [2 of 2] (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Jamestown - Yorktown Foundation (Folder 39, Box 3)
  - John Russell [1 of 2] (Folder 40A, Box 3)
  - Judges [2 of 2] 1991 (Folder 40B, Box 3)
  - Legislative Overview (Folder 41, Box 3)
  - Leslie Byrne [1 of 3] (Folder 42, Box 3)
  - Leslie Byrne [2 of 3] (Folder 43, Box 3)
  - Leslie Byrne [3 of 3] (Folder 44, Box 3)
  - HB 1071 Limitations on Punitive Damage (Folder 45, Box 3)
  - Lobbyists 1991 (Folder 46, Box 3)
  - Lottery (Folder 47, Box 3)
  - Mothers Against Drunk Driving [MADD] (Folder 48, Box 3)
  - Malpractice [Medical] (Folder 49, Box 3)
  - Medical College of Virginia [MCV] (Folder 50, Box 3)
  - Medical Aid and Medicare (Folder 51, Box 3)
  - Mental Health (Folder 52, Box 3)
  - Mental Health - Children out of State Placement (Folder 53, Box 3)
  - Mental Health Public Hearing 1990-1996 Plan 1990 - 1996 (Folder 54, Box 3)
  - Department of Mental Health ,Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services (Folder 55, Box 3)
  - Mental Health,Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services - Speech (Folder 56, Box 3)
  - Mental Retardation Staffing Study (Folder 57, Box 3)
  - Merrifield Business Association (Folder 58, Box 3)
  - Minorities [Northern Virginia Minority Business and Professional Association] (Folder 59, Box 3)
  - Mobil Oil Corporation (Folder 60, Box 3)
  - Model General Assembly (Folder 61, Box 3)
  - Mortgage Bankers Association (Folder 62, Box 3)
  - Nacfam - [National Coalition for Flexible Automated Manufacturing] (Folder 63, Box 3)
  - National Association of Retired Federal Employees- [NARFE] (Folder 64, Box 3)
  - National Rifle Association - NRA (Folder 65, Box 3)
  - National Women's Political Caucus- Virginia (Folder 66, Box 3)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures ,Labor Committee [1 of 2] (Folder 67, Box 3)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures ,Labor Committee [2 of 2] (Folder 68, Box 3)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures [1 of 2] (Folder 69, Box 3)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures [2 of 2] (Folder 70, Box 3)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures Questionnaire [NCSL] (Folder 71, Box 3)
  - Maternal and Child Health (Folder 72, Box 3)
  - The George Washington Boyhood Home Foundation (Folder 73, Box 3)
  - NCSL Task Force on Developmental Disabilities [1 of 3] (Folder 1, Box 4)
  - NCSL Task Force on Developmental Disabilities [2 of 3] (Folder 2, Box 4)
  - NCSL Task Force on Developmental Disabilities [3 of 3] (Folder 3, Box 4)
  - NCSL Women's Network (Folder 4, Box 4)
  - National Energy Education Development - NEED (Folder 5, Box 4)
  - Emilie F.Miller Newsletter 1988 (Folder 6, Box 4)
  - Emilie.F.Miller Newsletter 1989 (Folder 7, Box 4)
  - Emilie F.Miller Newsletter 1990 (Folder 8, Box 4)
  - Newsletter [Others] 1991 (Folder 9, Box 4)
  - Newsletter Samples, General Assembly (Folder 10, Box 4)
  - Noise Barriers [1 of 2] (Folder 11, Box 4)
  - Noise Barriers [2 of 2] (Folder 12, Box 4)
  - Non-Profit Organizations [Article] (Folder 13, Box 4)
  - Northern Virginia Board of Realtors (Folder 14, Box 4)
  - Northern Virginia Building Industry (Folder 15, Box 4)
  - Northern Virginia Community College [ Proposed State Funding Cuts] 1990 (Folder 16, Box 4)
  - Northern Virginia Delegation [1 of 3] 1991 (Folder 17, Box 4)
  - Northern Virginia Delegation [2 of 3] 1991 (Folder 18, Box 4)
  - Northern Virginia Delegation [3 of 3] 1991 (Folder 19, Box 4)
  - Northern Virginia Planning District Commission (Folder 20, Box 4)
  - Northern Virginia Regional Park Authority (Folder 21, Box 4)
  - Northern Virginia Sun Editorial Book (Folder 22, Box 4)
  - Northern Virginia Training Center (Folder 23, Box 4)
  - Northern Virginia Transportation Alliance (Folder 24, Box 4)
  - Northern Virginia Youth Symphony Association (Folder 25, Box 4)
  - National Order of Women Legislators - NOWL [ 1 OF 2] (Folder 26, Box 4)
  - National Order of Women Legislators - NOWL [2 OF 2] (Folder 27, Box 4)
  - National Organization for Women - NOW (Folder 28, Box 4)
  - Nuclear Medicines Speakers Bureau (Folder 29, Box 4)
  - Nurses [Virginia Nurses Association] 1989 (Folder 30, Box 4)
  - S.B. 235, Open Supply and Divorcement [1 of 3] 1990 - 1991 (Folder 31, Box 4)
  - S.B. 235, Open Supply and Divorcement [2 of 3] 1990 - 1991 (Folder 32, Box 4)
  - S.B. 235, Open Supply and Divorcement [3 of 3] 1990 - 1991 (Folder 33, Box 4)
  - Virginia Society of Opthalmology (Folder 34, Box 4)
  - Optometry [House Bill and Reports] (Folder 35, Box 4)
  - Pages - Capitol Hill,D.C. [Congressional Page Program] (Folder 36, Box 4)
  - Pap Smear Testing - Legislative Correspondence (Folder 37, Box 4)
  - Parental Leave or Family Leave (Folder 38, Box 4)
  - Parental Notification Study [1 of 2] (Folder 39, Box 4)
  - Parental Notification Study [2 of 2] (Folder 40, Box 4)
  - Parents for Compliance (Folder 41, Box 4)
  - Paul VI High School (Folder 42, Box 4)
  - Pay Equity (Folder 43, Box 4)
  - News Clipping [ 1 of 2] (Folder 44, Box 4)
  - News Clipping [2 of 2] (Folder 45, Box 4)
  - News clipping and Articles (Folder 46, Box 4)
  - Newsletter (Folder 47, Box 4)
  - Peanuts Veterinary Bill (Folder 1, Box 5)
  - Pension - Originals to respond to Inquiries (Folder 2, Box 5)
  - Pension [1 of 2] (Folder 3, Box 5)
  - Pension [2 of 2] (Folder 4, Box 5)
  - Peter Halpin (Folder 5, Box 5)
  - Personalities (Folder 6, Box 5)
  - Pesticides (Folder 7, Box 5)
  - Pharmacists (Folder 8, Box 5)
  - Phi Gamma Nu (Folder 9, Box 5)
  - Phillip Morris - Business and Labor Statistics in Virginia (Folder 10, Box 5)
  - Photos (Folder 11, Box 5)
  - Planning Districts (Folder 12, Box 5)
  - Parents of Children with Down Syndrome- PODS (Folder 13, Box 5)
  - Polls (Folder 14, Box 5)
  - Polygraph Tests (Folder 15, Box 5)
  - Portfolio of State Issues (Folder 16, Box 5)
  - Postal Information (Folder 17, Box 5)
  - POW/MIA Issue (Folder 18, Box 5)
  - Original Precinct File Form (Folder 19, Box 5)
  - Prescription Drug Program (Folder 20, Box 5)
  - Press Release, Re:Mobil Scholarship Fund for Returning Soldiers 1991 (Folder 21, Box 5)
  - Press Releases [1 of 2] (Folder 22, Box 5)
  - Press Releases [2 of 2] (Folder 23, Box 5)
  - Prevention Resource Materials (Folder 24, Box 5)
  - Printing Industry [1 of 2] (Folder 25, Box 5)
  - Printing Industry [2 of 2] (Folder 26, Box 5)
  - Prisons (Folder 27, Box 5)
  - Privatization [Annual Report] (Folder 28, Box 5)
  - Proffers Legislation [comments] (Folder 29, Box 5)
  - Project Update (Folder 30, Box 5)
  - Prompt Pay [ Legislation Report] (Folder 31, Box 5)
  - Psychologists (Folder 32, Box 5)
  - PTA's - Fairfax County Listing (Folder 33, Box 5)
  - Public Hearing [1 of 2] January 5,1991 (Folder 34, Box 5)
  - Public Hearing [2 of 2] January 5,1991 (Folder 35, Box 5)
  - Public Hearing before Northern Virginia Delegation [1 of 2] January 6, 1990 (Folder 36, Box 5)
  - Public Hearing before Northern Virginia Delegation [2 of 2] January 6, 1990 (Folder 37, Box 5)
  - Public Hearing - Thank You Letters January 6, 1990 (Folder 38, Box 5)
  - Radon [Health Risk Which Causes Lung Cancer] (Folder 39, Box 5)
  - RailRoad CSX-RFP (Folder 40, Box 5)
  - Real Estate Appraiser Regulations (Folder 41, Box 5)
  - Reapportionment - Census Figures ,Restricting Plans [1 of 2] (Folder 42, Box 5)
  - Reapportionment - Census Figures ,Restricting Plans [2 of 2] (Folder 43, Box 5)
  - Recommendations [1 of 2] (Folder 44, Box 5)
  - Recommendations [2 of 2] (Folder 45, Box 5)
  - Registrar's [Listing] (Folder 1, Box 6)
  - Republican Party (Folder 2, Box 6)
  - Resource Mothers Program (Folder 3, Box 6)
  - Resume of Emilie F.Miller [2 copies] (Folder 4, Box 6)
  - Resumes [1 of 4] (Folder 5, Box 6)
  - Resumes [2 of 4] (Folder 6, Box 6)
  - Resumes [3 of 4] (Folder 7, Box 6)
  - Resumes [4 of 4] (Folder 8, Box 6)
  - Reverend Creedon - Social Worker of the Year 1989 (Folder 9, Box 6)